Guide to the Ernst A. Evans Manuscript Sheet Music circa 1930s
Pacific University Archives
Ernst A. Evans Manuscript Sheet Music
circa 1930s
MS.42
Pacific University, Archives http://www.pacificu.edu/library/services/archives/ 2043 College Way Forest Grove, OR, 97116 503-352-1405 archives@pacificu.edu
1.0 cubic feet 1 box
Ernst A. Evans, Master and Doctor of Music, was a Professor of Pipe Organ and Music Theory at Washington State College at Pullman in the 1910s. The collection is comprised of manuscript music scores and parts chiefly for keyboard and voice.
Evans, Ernst Arthur
Collection is open for research.
No accruals are expected.
Biographical Note
Ernst A. Evans, Master and Doctor of Music, was a Professor of Pipe Organ and Music Theory at Washington State College at Pullman in the 1910s. He had previously been an Examiner at the Victoria College of Music, presumably in British Columbia. He was a Fellow of the Incorporated Guild of Church Musicians in London. He composed many works which do not appear to have been published. His extant manuscripts are mostly sacred works.
The collection is comprised of manuscript music scores and parts composed by Ernst A. Evans, chiefly for keyboard and voice. Most of the works are sacred music. Several of the compositions include scores for multiple voice parts. Also present is a broadside advertising the performance of his piece "Seven Last Words" at the Saint Davids Episcopal Church in Portland.
This collection came into the hands of Edward and Lucile Evans Hargreaves, who were Pacific University graduates and staff. They donated the material to Pacific University in 1993.
Music
- Seven Last Words broadside, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Seven Last Words manuscript score and parts, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
- Christmas Cantata: God's Gift manuscript score and parts, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
- Patmos manuscript score, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Star of Night manuscript score and parts, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Plains of Bethlehem manuscript score and parts, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Daybreak manuscript score and parts, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sonata in D Minor for Organ, op.52 manuscript score, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lamia, op.54 manuscript score and parts, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Overture, op.20 manuscript score and parts, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Simple Simon manuscript score, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Psalm 37, op.123 manuscript score and parts, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous and unidentifed fragments, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Research Notes, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 18)